<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Vanity TLD</title>
	<subtitle>Vanity Domain</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/"/>
	<updated>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://example.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>self@garytrakhman.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>New blog</title>
		<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://garytrakhman.com/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to bring back my TLD, and I&#39;ve been meaning to blog again&lt;br /&gt;
after a long hiatus. I don&#39;t have anything specific to write about&lt;br /&gt;
yet, but I do get opinionated about technical topics and occasionally&lt;br /&gt;
nontechnical topics as well.  My previous (now deleted) blog&#39;s purpose&lt;br /&gt;
was to self-promote and further my development career. In 2010 this&lt;br /&gt;
seemed like a good idea, but many others have also had that same idea&lt;br /&gt;
since then. Consequently, there&#39;s a lot of content that I have trouble&lt;br /&gt;
motivating myself to read.  There are a lot of intro-level articles&lt;br /&gt;
made by and for the new developer.  Occasionally, I can also find&lt;br /&gt;
something more specialized and difficult that seems interesting. At&lt;br /&gt;
this point I&#39;m too impatient for the easy reads and after paying&lt;br /&gt;
attention for a minute or two will jump into skim mode to see if&lt;br /&gt;
there&#39;s anything worth a closer look.  For the harder reads, I either&lt;br /&gt;
know too little about the topic or it would be too risky to apply in&lt;br /&gt;
my place of work, so it can feel largely useless at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, twitter replaced blogging and reading blogs for me.&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately, while it is a nice way to find content and keep up with&lt;br /&gt;
people, it promotes distracted thought. I think most can agree that&lt;br /&gt;
when writing larger blocks of text, you can more easily clarify each&lt;br /&gt;
thought and test it against your other thoughts to see if makes&lt;br /&gt;
sense. With the smaller format, it seems like I&#39;m susceptible to&lt;br /&gt;
interruption by (probably also distracted) people posting in&lt;br /&gt;
real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I ask myself what&#39;s the purpose of this blog, I think it&#39;s to&lt;br /&gt;
remove those distractions from my own thought process and to rebuild&lt;br /&gt;
my own reading and writing habits.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
