<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Vanity TLD</title>
	<subtitle>Vanity Domain</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/"/>
	<updated>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://example.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Your Name Here</name>
		<email>self@garytrakhman.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>New blog.</title>
		<link href="https://garytrakhman.com/posts/firstpost/"/>
		<updated>2021-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://garytrakhman.com/posts/firstpost/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to bring back my TLD, and I&#39;ve been meaning to blog again&lt;br /&gt;
after a long hiatus. It&#39;s not that I have anything specific to write&lt;br /&gt;
about yet, but I do get opinionated about technical topics and&lt;br /&gt;
occasionally nontechnical topics as well.  The initial blog&#39;s (now&lt;br /&gt;
deleted) purpose was to get my foot in the door into a tech career.&lt;br /&gt;
It was tech marketing. In 2010 this seemed like a good idea, but I&lt;br /&gt;
think a lot of other people had that idea since then. Consequently,&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;ve had trouble finding consistent tech blogs that I was motivated to&lt;br /&gt;
read.  There are a lot of intro-level articles made by and for the new&lt;br /&gt;
developer. Additionally, I can find something good to read on some&lt;br /&gt;
very specialized topics. At this point I&#39;m too impatient for the easy&lt;br /&gt;
reads.  For the harder reads, I either know too little about the topic&lt;br /&gt;
or would try to avoid the risk of applying it in my place of work, so&lt;br /&gt;
it can feel largely useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, twitter largely replaced blogging and reading blogs for&lt;br /&gt;
me. Unfortunately, I think while it is a nice way to find content and&lt;br /&gt;
keep up with people, it promotes distracted thought. I think most can&lt;br /&gt;
agree that when writing larger blocks, you can more easily clarify each&lt;br /&gt;
thought and test it against others. With the smaller format, it seems&lt;br /&gt;
like I&#39;m susceptible to interruption by (probably also distracted)&lt;br /&gt;
people posting in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I ask myself what&#39;s the purpose of this blog, I think it&#39;s to&lt;br /&gt;
remove those distractions from my own thought process and to rebuild&lt;br /&gt;
my own reading and writing habits.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
